<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Kage</title>
    <link>https://kage.xyz/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Kage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 10:25:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kage.xyz/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo - Day 006</title>
      <link>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-07_nanowrimo_day_006/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 10:25:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-07_nanowrimo_day_006/</guid>
      <description>7973 Yesterday I failed to meet my word count again&amp;hellip; But at least I wrote something. My hope is that in the weekend I will be able to catch up&amp;hellip;
I have been trying to understand my characters better. Some people write extensive descriptions of everyone, with their birthdays, physical appearance, backstory&amp;hellip; Others write an interview, I am trying something similar. Everyday in the bus, on my way to work, I imagine that one of my characters is sitting by my side and I try to have a conversation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo - Day 005</title>
      <link>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-06_nanowrimo_day_005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 14:10:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-06_nanowrimo_day_005/</guid>
      <description>6926 So&amp;hellip; I wrote nothing yesterday. I had things to do, bla bla bla&amp;hellip;
I hope that this is the first and last time that this happens, at least this month. The 1667 words are at my limit, both in creative terms and in time available, so if I fail to meet my goal in one day, it becomes really hard to catch up again&amp;hellip;
NaNoWriMo is stressful, but that&amp;rsquo;s the point, you need to prove to yourself that you can do it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo - Day 004</title>
      <link>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-05_nanowrimo_day_004/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 16:04:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-05_nanowrimo_day_004/</guid>
      <description>6926 Yesterday I wrote a little less than 1667 words, but I had reached the and of a chapter and thought that would be a good place to stop. I think that is okay since I am still on schedule.
I followed my plan and wrote a chapter focused on Lyza, my main character. I believe that it worked, and I fell like I know her a little better now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo - Day 003</title>
      <link>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-04_nanowrimo_day_003/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 11:02:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-04_nanowrimo_day_003/</guid>
      <description>5477 Day 3 did not start well, I sat down and had no idea of what to write about. It took me almost an hour but I finally had an idea and, for my surprise, writing the words for the day was surprisingly easy.
I think this is further evidence that waiting for inspiration to strike is a very efficient way of writing nothing, sit down long enough and some idea will come, it may not be the best idea in the world but it is an idea, and that&amp;rsquo;s what you need to start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo - Day 002</title>
      <link>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-03_nanowrimo_day_002/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 10:59:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-03_nanowrimo_day_002/</guid>
      <description>3619 Success! Yesterday I was able to catch up if my word count count goal, I even went a little further and wrote 285 extra words! Only 46381 words left to go!
That&amp;rsquo;s the good news, the bad news is I have already come across a serious problem. I had a scene with a heavy exposition, so I decided to make divide it in two, that also worked towards giving the main character time to think about what she had learned and decide for herself if she was going to believe it or not, so far so good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo - Day 001</title>
      <link>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-02_nanowrimo_day_001/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 14:19:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kage.xyz/2017-11-02_nanowrimo_day_001/</guid>
      <description>964 Day one went better than I was expecting. I thought that by word 500 I would give up, but no, in fact I only stopped because It was late and I needed to sleep. Still, 964 is less than my daily goal of 1667 and that&amp;rsquo;s a problem. Luckily for me I will have more free time today, so I should be able to catch up.
As I said before and did not make an outline but writing some ideas down helped me get a better grasp of the world and characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Tools</title>
      <link>https://kage.xyz/2017-10-30_writing_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 22:29:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kage.xyz/2017-10-30_writing_tools/</guid>
      <description>Most people use computers to write nowadays, and that make a lot of sense. For me, though, writing on a computer is a bit difficult, I get bored and distracted very easily and in a computer, where the whole of the Internet is a click away, I am not able to be very productive&amp;hellip;
So I have decided to write my NaNoWriMo novel by hand! Seeing the letters form on the page, with some music on the background, seems to be enough to keep my brain entertained while I write, and the lack of distractions help a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cover and Synopsis</title>
      <link>https://kage.xyz/2017-10-29_cover_and_synopsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 20:42:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kage.xyz/2017-10-29_cover_and_synopsis/</guid>
      <description>This is my first idea for the cover of my novel, what do you think about it? I should probably be working on the story instead of the cover but the empty rectangle on the NoNoWriMo page was annoying me&amp;hellip;
This year I will be a Pantser! No time to waste with outlines, raw untamed creativity is the way to go, MUAHAHAAHHAHAHA!
This is the synopsis of what I am thinking about writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo</title>
      <link>https://kage.xyz/2017-10-28_nanowrimo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 11:47:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kage.xyz/2017-10-28_nanowrimo/</guid>
      <description>This year I have decided to participate on NaNoWriMo (in NaNoWriMo?). For those of you that don&amp;rsquo;t know, NaNoWriMo is a sort of &amp;hellip; contest? The objective is to write a complete novel, 50000 words or more, during the month of November. Everybody that is able to do so is considered a winner. You can find their Wikipedia page HERE and their website HERE.
Fifty thousand words, thirty days, 1667 words per day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>